<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The McCann Lab</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The McCann Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mccannlab.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Homogenization of freshwater lakes</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/</guid><description>🇺🇸 What happened to fish communities in Ontario lakes over the last few decades? We have been relentlessly looking for answers to this question! Indeed, we did our best to determine whether global change has affected those communities over the last 40 years. It turns out that fish communities in Ontario lakes are pretty different from what they were, but climate change does not explain those changes 💥! But, but… how can we say that?</description></item><item><title>McCann lab in Federicton for the CSEE</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2018/08/18/mccann-lab-in-federicton-for-the-csee/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2018/08/18/mccann-lab-in-federicton-for-the-csee/</guid><description>They've made it 🎆! That was a LONG drive, but we made it to Fredericton for @CSEE_Meetings #EcoEvoEnto2019 !@mccannlab @bragrah @marie_gutgesell pic.twitter.com/AjBDoCDOJT
&amp;mdash; Carling Bieg (@carlingbieg) August 18, 2019 Six relentless lab members traveled from Guelph to Fredericton by 🚗, to attend the CSEE, ESC, &amp;amp; AES 2019 Joint Meeting, what a trip! Do not miss their talks! Carling Bieg : Wednesday 21 August 2019 &amp;ndash; 10:45-11:00</description></item><item><title>Git, GitHub &amp; GitKraken</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2018/05/18/git-github-gitkraken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2018/05/18/git-github-gitkraken/</guid><description>Context With the increasing amount of data available and the increasing complexity of statistical analyses, nowadays a PhD in ecology often requires programming skills. Coding comes with challenges to be tackled to do science and good practices to be mastered to do reproducible science.
Git is a powerful tool that keeps track of earlier development stages of their code, it also ease the team work on a specific project. Technically speaking, is a Distributed Version Control Systems (DVCS): every contributor has his one copy of the code, its complete history and comes with powerful tools to version your code, create branches, compare versions and branches, etc.</description></item><item><title>Smart Food Webs</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2017/04/11/smart-food-webs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2017/04/11/smart-food-webs/</guid><description>Smart Fish, as measured by relative brain size, are found in the food web in positions that are expected to maximize the stability of ecosystems
A food web is a map of species interactions describing who eats whom. The network of species interactions that comprise a food web are now known to be incredibly baroque entities that extend across a mosaic of habitat divisions and ecosystems. As an example, bears forage in oceans, rivers and terrestrial habitats blurring the lines between ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Biodiversity and Biostructure</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/12/monitoring-biodiversity-and-biostructure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/12/monitoring-biodiversity-and-biostructure/</guid><description>A recent article by Dr. Bailey McMeans and others argues that there is a consistent response of biodiversity to human impacts, from individual level attributes to whole ecosystems. This integration across scales, seldom considered in a discipline often separated by scales suggests that there exists an overarching framework for biomonitoring ecosystems under human impact. The paper is is published in Ecological Monographs.</description></item><item><title>From modules to whole webs</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/11/from-modules-to-whole-webs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/11/from-modules-to-whole-webs/</guid><description>Past lab member Dr. Gabriel Gellner, now in University of California Davis with Alan Hastings, publishes a theoretical paper on the role of growth, energy and interaction strength on modules to whole matrices with PI Kevin McCann (paper on researchgate). Gellner shows that while recent results have found potential differences that there is actually a consistent dynamical response (in terms of local stability analysis) from very simple low species models to speciose whole food webs.</description></item><item><title>Duality of Nature's Stability</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/09/duality-of-natures-stability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/post/2016/06/09/duality-of-natures-stability/</guid><description>A recent lab paper by ex Ph.D. student (now PDF with Alan Hastings) Dr. Gabriel Gellner on how there exist two types of responses to increased energy flow in the basic C-R interaction. This duality in response (excitable and non-excitable dynamics) are then used to delineate two qualitatively different types of response to stochasticity. This work surprisingly suggests that the Lotka-volterra with &amp;ldquo;noise&amp;rdquo; tends to behave very similarly to the Rosenzweig-MacArthur in that a stochastic Hopf (sensu Arnold; Fig.</description></item></channel></rss>