<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Members on The McCann Lab</title><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/</link><description>Recent content in Members on The McCann Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:36:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mccannlab.github.io/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/aidan_maloney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/aidan_maloney/</guid><description>I am an MSc candidate in the McCann and MacDougall labs, studying the relationship between bat activity and agricultural intensity in southwestern Ontario. This will broadly examine how a perturbation to the landscape, through homogenization, may result in a loss of asynchronous resource availability for a highly mobile generalist consumer. I completed my undergraduate degree at the University of Guelph, majoring in Ecology. I became interested in community ecology after taking the course Populations, Communities, and Ecosystems, which opened my eyes to the interconnectedness and balanced nature of biodiversity.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/alexa_scott/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/alexa_scott/</guid><description>In the McCann Lab, I am completing a thesis based masters in Integrative Biology at the University of Guelph. While completing my undergraduate degree in Wildlife Biology and Conservation with a math minor, I became fascinated by how species coexistence can be modelled mathematically. Within my MSc, I am using theory to understand how seasonality may drive species coexistence. By altering seasonal lengths to resemble global warming, my research aims to investigate if and how competitive species can coexist in the face of climate change</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/brandon_graham/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/brandon_graham/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/carling_bieg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/carling_bieg/</guid><description>I am a PhD student in the McCann Lab, co-advised by Evan Fraser from the Department of Geography. I use theory to understand ecosystem functioning in order to preserve both ecological stability and food production in the face of global change (e.g., climate change, land development and food production/harvesting). My past research has focused on patterns in global fisheries and resulting food web dynamics, and I am now extending this by developing general theory that can be applied to many ecosystem types, from temperate rivers to tropical flood plains and coral reefs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/charlotte_ward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/charlotte_ward/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/christopher_greysongaito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/christopher_greysongaito/</guid><description>I am fascinated by systems; how they function, what structures them, and what causes them to fail. My favourite systems are ecological systems and my specific research focus is ecological food webs. However, I see myself as highly interdisciplinary and am interested in the intersection of ecology with evolution, politics, and economics. My main research tool is mathematical modelling, but I also collaborate with empiricists regularly.
For my PhD, I am examining the interactions of ecological processes across scales in a variety of systems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/emily_champage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/emily_champage/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/gabriel_gellner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/gabriel_gellner/</guid><description>I study the structure and functions of food webs to better understand our environment and biological complexity. Topics include theoretical ecology, population biology and how biodiversity affects ecological systems. As well, I’m interested in where the ideas and methods of theoretical ecology and ecoinformatics come from, and how they are applied. For more details visit my website.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/kevin_cazelles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/kevin_cazelles/</guid><description>I am a post-doctoral fellow with a wide range of interests in ecology. I regard myself as a theoretician motivated by a strong desire to apply the results of abstract investigations to tangible challenges such as the impact of global change on ecological communities.
During my PhD, I investigated the relationship between biotic interactions and species co-occurrence. Even though the role of species interactions have been been early pointed out as a major contributor to species's range limits, researchers are still struggling to find adequate approaches that appropriately combine abiotic and biotic factors to better predict tomorrow's biodiversity.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/marie_gutgesell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/marie_gutgesell/</guid><description>I am a PhD student in the McCann Lab.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/reilly_oconnor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/reilly_oconnor/</guid><description>I am an MSc candidate in the McCann Lab, studying spatial and temporal population dynamics of zooplankton in Lake Simcoe, ON. I completed my undergraduate degree at the University of Guelph in Marine and Freshwater Biology with a minor in Ecology. Throughout my degree, I became interested in lake food web ecology through working on Lake Huron as a field and lab technician in the McCann Lab. Currently, I am looking at how variation in densities of the Lake Simcoe zooplankton community have changed since 1986.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/timothy_bartley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mccannlab.github.io/members/timothy_bartley/</guid><description>I am a food web ecologist studying the causes and consequences of food web reorganization with global environmental change.
Currently, I am postdoctoral fellow at the University or Toronto Mississauga and the University of Guelph. I am integrating a range of empirical data, primarily from the Great Lakes and other aquatic ecosystems, to document how the organisms&amp;rsquo; responses to global environmental change are &amp;lsquo;rewiring&amp;rsquo; food webs. I am also developing theoretical models to explore how this food web rewiring impacts stability.</description></item></channel></rss>